A Guide to the Papers of Harry Flood Byrd, Jr., 1966-1971
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Harry Flood Byrd, Jr., 1966-1971
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10320-f
This collection contains ca. 2,000 items (3 Hollinger boxes, ca. 1 linear foot).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to the Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Papers is controlled by the Honorable Harry F. Byrd, Jr. An applicant for access who is not associated with the University of Virginia must furnish to the Director of Special Collections a brief description of his academic or other qualifications, a summary of his research project, and a description of any projected publication that might make use of material from, or material derived from, the Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Papers. The Director of Special Collections will contact Senator Byrd and will notify the applicant of the Senator's decision.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. in October 2000.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr., ca. 2,000 items (3 Hollinger boxes, ca. 1 linear foot), 1966-1971, contains campaign contribution contact cards, 1966-1970; card files of Democratic leaders; a political news clippings file, 1968-1969; and miscellaneous material from the 1970 Virginians for Byrd campaign including campaign handbook, news releases, advertising, financial report, posters, brochures, and bumper stickers.
Contents List
- Campaign Material
  - Advertising 1970 (Box 1)
  - Adveritising Supplement [1970] (Box 1)
  - American Conservative Union District Action Handbook ca. 1970 (Box 1)
  - Bumper Stickers and Brochures [1970] (Box 1)
  - "Factual Campaign Information" Government Document 1970 (Box 1)
  - Financial Report for Virginians for Byrd by Cargill, Wilson & Acree, Inc. Advertising 1971 Jan, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - News Releases by Virginians for Byrd 1970 Sep - Nov, n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Radio Recap Virginians for Byrd 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Senator Byrd for Virginia" Re-election Campaign Posters and Boards 1970 (Oversize T-14)
  - Television Recap Virginians for Byrd 1970 (Box 1)
  - Two different Sample Campaign Posters with changes and corrections; one for Virginians for Byrd and the other for Democrats for Byrd ca. 1970 (Oversize T-14)
  - Two Book jackets for Defying the Odds An Independent Senator's Historic Campaign by Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr. n.d. (Oversize T-14)
- News Clippings re Politics
  - News clippings 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - Bond Issue 1968 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - Democratic National Convention, Chicago, Illinois 1968 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - Democratic Party 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - Election Results 1968 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - Poverty Program 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - Presidential Election 1968, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - News clippings - Republican Party 1968 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - William C. Battle 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - Joel T. Broyhill v David B. Kinney 1968 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - Thomas N. Downing 1968 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - Henry E. Howell, Jr. 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - John O. Marsh, Jr. v A.R. "Peter" Giesen 1968 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - William L. Scott v Andrew H. McCutcheon 1968 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - Frederick T. Stant, Jr. v G. William Whitehurst 1968 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - Weldon W. Tuck v W.C. "Dan" Daniel 1968 (Box 3)
  - News clippings - Virginia Elections - William C. Wampler v Joe P. Johnson 1968 (Box 3)
- Index Cards
  - Political Cards A-Z with Names of Chairmen, etc. n.d.
  - Campaign Contribution Contact Cards 1966-1970
  - Campaign Contribution Contact Cards A-Z, in alphabetical order 1970
  - Campaign Contribution Contact Cards, no order 1970